## MANIKANDAN R S

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

### **About Me**

As a Developer with 2 years of experience in the IT industry, I have a strong understanding of how technology can be leveraged to improve technical services. My expertise lies in developing and maintaining applications ensuring that they are working efficiently and effectively for clients.

To build a career where my creativity and skills can be utilized in the field of Information Technology, being a positiveteam player, I always like to learn and upgrade myself at every opportunity and contribute maximum towards teamwork and goal setting for achieving targets.

# Experience

### Cognizant Technology Solutions

Jan 2022 - Present

Junior Software Engineer.

#### **Project Experience**

Title : Junior Software Engineer

Client : Bayer Corporation

**Duration**: Aug 2022 - till Date

#### Technologies used

.net,MVC,SQL

node.js,react.js

mongoDB

#### **Roles & Responsibilities**

- Worked in application related issues and resolved within SLA.
- Involved in Analysis, coding, deployments & testing of demands, Incidents and Ticket handling.
- Testing the application along with other team members fixes to ensure there are no breakages in existing system.
- Knowledge on end to end process related to Change management, Service Tasks

Education Aug 2018 - Apr 2022

Bachelor's degree in Electronics and Communication Engineering PSNA College of Engineering and Technology, Dindigul. CGPA-8.4

CSI Pasumalai Boys. Hr. Sec School SSLC (10th) - 2016- 93% 12th - 2018 - 80%

# Skills

- ASP.NET MVC/ C#/ Web API
- HTML/CSS/React
- Express.js/mongo DB
- GIT/ GitHub
- Production Support
- VS / VS Code

# Language

- English (fluent)
- Tamil
- Saurashtra

## Contact

- **(**) +918428148814
- manik9092526954@gmail.com



1/935 A, Anna Nagar, Kaithari Nagar,

Madurai - 625005

in linkedin.com/in/Manikandan-r-s-2031501b3